<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://www.w3.org/WAI/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://www.w3.org/WAI/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-08-25T21:00:06+00:00</updated><id>https://www.w3.org/WAI/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Web Accessibility Initiative (WAI)</title><subtitle>The Website of the World Wide Web Consortium’s Web Accessibility Initiative.
</subtitle><author><name>W3C Web Accessibility Initiative (WAI)</name></author><entry><title type="html">Invitation: WAI-Tools Online Meeting 22 September 2020</title><link href="https://www.w3.org/WAI/news/2020-08-24/WAI-Tools_meeting_September/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Invitation: WAI-Tools Online Meeting 22 September 2020" /><published>2020-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.w3.org/WAI/news/2020-08-24/WAI-Tools_meeting_September</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.w3.org/WAI/news/2020-08-24/WAI-Tools_meeting_September/">&lt;p&gt;You are invited to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.w3.org/WAI/about/projects/wai-tools/third-open-meeting/&quot;&gt;WAI-Tools Online Open Meeting on 22 September 2020&lt;/a&gt;. The meeting is intended for web accessibility practitioners, evaluation and quality assurance tool vendors, website owners, European monitoring bodies, researchers, and users interested in large-scale monitoring of web accessibility. Agenda, logistics, and registration information is in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.w3.org/WAI/about/projects/wai-tools/third-open-meeting/&quot;&gt;meeting page&lt;/a&gt;. This meeting is free, and registration is required.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>W3C Web Accessibility Initiative (WAI)</name></author><summary type="html">You are invited to the WAI-Tools Online Open Meeting on 22 September 2020. The meeting is intended for web accessibility practitioners, evaluation and quality assurance tool vendors, website owners, European monitoring bodies, researchers, and users interested in large-scale monitoring of web accessibility. Agenda, logistics, and registration information is in the meeting page. This meeting is free, and registration is required.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">For Wide Review: Web Content Accessibility Guidelines (WCAG) 2.2 Working Draft</title><link href="https://www.w3.org/WAI/news/2020-08-11/wcag-2-2/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="For Wide Review: Web Content Accessibility Guidelines (WCAG) 2.2 Working Draft" /><published>2020-08-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-08-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.w3.org/WAI/news/2020-08-11/wcag-2-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.w3.org/WAI/news/2020-08-11/wcag-2-2/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.w3.org/TR/WCAG22/&quot;&gt;WCAG 2.2 Working Draft&lt;/a&gt; is ready wide review before finalizing WCAG 2.2. This version has 9 new “success criteria”  (requirements) since WCAG 2.1. The new success criteria address user needs of people with cognitive or learning disabilities, users of mobile devices, and users of ebooks. We want to hear from users, authors, tool developers, policy makers, and others about benefits from the new proposed success criteria, as well as how achievable you feel it is to conform to the new success criteria. Additional information is in the blog post &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.w3.org/blog/2020/08/wcag22-wide-review/&quot;&gt;Web Content Accessibility Guidelines (WCAG) 2.2 Draft for Review&lt;/a&gt;. Please submit comments by 18 September 2020.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>W3C Web Accessibility Initiative (WAI)</name></author><summary type="html">WCAG 2.2 Working Draft is ready wide review before finalizing WCAG 2.2. This version has 9 new “success criteria” (requirements) since WCAG 2.1. The new success criteria address user needs of people with cognitive or learning disabilities, users of mobile devices, and users of ebooks. We want to hear from users, authors, tool developers, policy makers, and others about benefits from the new proposed success criteria, as well as how achievable you feel it is to conform to the new success criteria. Additional information is in the blog post Web Content Accessibility Guidelines (WCAG) 2.2 Draft for Review. Please submit comments by 18 September 2020.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">For Review: Making Content Usable for People with Cognitive and Learning Disabilities</title><link href="https://www.w3.org/WAI/news/2020-07-17/content-usable/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="For Review: Making Content Usable for People with Cognitive and Learning Disabilities" /><published>2020-07-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-07-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.w3.org/WAI/news/2020-07-17/content-usable</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.w3.org/WAI/news/2020-07-17/content-usable/">&lt;p&gt;The Draft Note &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.w3.org/TR/coga-usable/&quot;&gt;&quot;Making Content Usable for People with Cognitive and Learning Disabilities&quot;&lt;/a&gt; is ready for review. This may be the final review before the document is published as a Working Group Note. We particularly request feedback on:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Are any user needs or patterns missing or incorrect?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Can any information be made easier to understand and implement?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments are welcome through 4 September 2020.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>W3C Web Accessibility Initiative (WAI)</name></author><summary type="html">The Draft Note &quot;Making Content Usable for People with Cognitive and Learning Disabilities&quot; is ready for review. This may be the final review before the document is published as a Working Group Note. We particularly request feedback on: Are any user needs or patterns missing or incorrect? Can any information be made easier to understand and implement? Comments are welcome through 4 September 2020.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">New Resource: Authoring Tool Accessibility Report Generator (keywords: CMS, ATAG, …)</title><link href="https://www.w3.org/WAI/news/2020-06-29/ATAG-Report-Tool/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New Resource: Authoring Tool Accessibility Report Generator (keywords: CMS, ATAG, ...) " /><published>2020-06-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-06-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.w3.org/WAI/news/2020-06-29/ATAG-Report-Tool</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.w3.org/WAI/news/2020-06-29/ATAG-Report-Tool/">&lt;p&gt;The Accessibility Education and Outreach Working Group (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.w3.org/WAI/EO/&quot;&gt;EOWG&lt;/a&gt;) has published the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.w3.org/WAI/atag/report-tool/&quot;&gt;ATAG Report Tool&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. Authoring tools are software and services used to create web content – such as content management systems (CMS) and what-you-see-is-what-you-get (WYSIWYG) HTML editors. W3C's Authoring Tool Accessibility Guidelines (ATAG) addresses making the authoring tools themselves accessible and helping authors create more accessible web content. Learn more from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.w3.org/WAI/standards-guidelines/atag/&quot;&gt;ATAG Overview&lt;/a&gt;. The new ATAG Report Tool helps authoring tool vendors and evaluators provide information to project managers, procurers, and others who need to know how well potential authoring tools support accessibility.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>W3C Web Accessibility Initiative (WAI)</name></author><summary type="html">The Accessibility Education and Outreach Working Group (EOWG) has published the ATAG Report Tool. Authoring tools are software and services used to create web content – such as content management systems (CMS) and what-you-see-is-what-you-get (WYSIWYG) HTML editors. W3C's Authoring Tool Accessibility Guidelines (ATAG) addresses making the authoring tools themselves accessible and helping authors create more accessible web content. Learn more from the ATAG Overview. The new ATAG Report Tool helps authoring tool vendors and evaluators provide information to project managers, procurers, and others who need to know how well potential authoring tools support accessibility.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">For Review: Challenges with Accessibility Guidelines Conformance and Testing, and Approaches for Mitigating Them</title><link href="https://www.w3.org/WAI/news/2020-06-19/conformance-challenges-approaches-for-mitigating/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="For Review: Challenges with Accessibility Guidelines Conformance and Testing, and Approaches for Mitigating Them" /><published>2020-06-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-06-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.w3.org/WAI/news/2020-06-19/conformance-challenges-approaches-for-mitigating</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.w3.org/WAI/news/2020-06-19/conformance-challenges-approaches-for-mitigating/">&lt;p&gt;The Accessibility Guidelines Working Group (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.w3.org/WAI/GL/&quot;&gt;AG WG&lt;/a&gt;) has published an updated &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.w3.org/TR/2020/WD-accessibility-conformance-challenges-20200619/&quot;&gt;Working Draft of Challenges with Accessibility Guidelines Conformance and Testing, and Approaches for Mitigating Them&lt;/a&gt;. This document is part of work on future accessibility guidelines, including WCAG 3.0. It explores the challenges of evaluating a broad range of websites and applications for conformance to Web Content Accessibility Guidelines (WCAG), and explores approaches for mitigating these challenges. Please see the blog post for information on this document and questions for review: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.w3.org/blog/2020/06/accessibility-conformance-challenges-draft/&quot;&gt;Challenges with Accessibility Guidelines Conformance and Testing, and Approaches for Mitigating Them - blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>W3C Web Accessibility Initiative (WAI)</name></author><summary type="html">The Accessibility Guidelines Working Group (AG WG) has published an updated Working Draft of Challenges with Accessibility Guidelines Conformance and Testing, and Approaches for Mitigating Them. This document is part of work on future accessibility guidelines, including WCAG 3.0. It explores the challenges of evaluating a broad range of websites and applications for conformance to Web Content Accessibility Guidelines (WCAG), and explores approaches for mitigating these challenges. Please see the blog post for information on this document and questions for review: Challenges with Accessibility Guidelines Conformance and Testing, and Approaches for Mitigating Them - blog.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">WCAG 2.1 in Dutch: Authorized Translation Published</title><link href="https://www.w3.org/WAI/news/2020-05-26/wcag-21-in-dutch/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="WCAG 2.1 in Dutch: Authorized Translation Published" /><published>2020-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.w3.org/WAI/news/2020-05-26/wcag-21-in-dutch</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.w3.org/WAI/news/2020-05-26/wcag-21-in-dutch/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.w3.org/Translations/WCAG21-nl/&quot; lang=&quot;nl&quot; hreflang=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;Richtlijnen voor Toegankelijkheid van Webcontent (WCAG) 2.1&lt;/a&gt;, the Dutch Authorized Translation of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.w3.org/WAI/intro/wcag&quot;&gt;Web Content Accessibility Guidelines (WCAG) 2.1&lt;/a&gt;, is now available, following completion of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2005/02/TranslationPolicy&quot;&gt;W3C Authorized Translations process&lt;/a&gt;. Other translations of WAI resources are listed in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.w3.org/WAI/translations/&quot;&gt;All WAI Translations&lt;/a&gt;. WAI encourages translations in all languages. If you might be interesting in translating resources, see &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.w3.org/WAI/about/translating/&quot;&gt;Translating WAI Resources&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>W3C Web Accessibility Initiative (WAI)</name></author><summary type="html">Richtlijnen voor Toegankelijkheid van Webcontent (WCAG) 2.1, the Dutch Authorized Translation of Web Content Accessibility Guidelines (WCAG) 2.1, is now available, following completion of the W3C Authorized Translations process. Other translations of WAI resources are listed in All WAI Translations. WAI encourages translations in all languages. If you might be interesting in translating resources, see Translating WAI Resources.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">New Videos Introduce Web Accessibility - Great for GAAD</title><link href="https://www.w3.org/WAI/news/2020-05-14/eval-videos-gaad/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New Videos Introduce Web Accessibility - Great for GAAD" /><published>2020-05-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-05-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.w3.org/WAI/news/2020-05-14/eval-videos-gaad</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.w3.org/WAI/news/2020-05-14/eval-videos-gaad/">&lt;p&gt;The Accessibility Education and Outreach Working Group (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.w3.org/WAI/EO/&quot;&gt;EOWG&lt;/a&gt;) has published &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.w3.org/WAI/test-evaluate/&quot;&gt;5 short videos that introduce evaluation resources&lt;/a&gt; from the W3C Web Accessibility Initiative (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.w3.org/WAI/&quot;&gt;WAI&lt;/a&gt;). The animated videos cover: Easy Checks — A First Review of Web Accessibility,  Evaluation Tools, Conformance Evaluation including the Report Tool, and Involving Users in Web Accessibility. Other WAI videos include: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.w3.org/WAI/videos/standards-and-benefits/&quot;&gt;Video Introduction to Web Accessibility and W3C Standards&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.w3.org/WAI/perspective-videos/&quot;&gt;Web Accessibility Perspectives videos&lt;/a&gt; that demonstrate how accessibility is essential for some and useful for all. These videos are particularly useful to share for Global Accessibility Awareness Day (&lt;a href=&quot;https://globalaccessibilityawarenessday.org/&quot;&gt;GAAD&lt;/a&gt;) on 21 May 2020 — along with the free online course: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.w3.org/blog/2019/12/free-online-course-introduction-to-web-accessibility/&quot;&gt;Introduction to Web Accessibility&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>W3C Web Accessibility Initiative (WAI)</name></author><summary type="html">The Accessibility Education and Outreach Working Group (EOWG) has published 5 short videos that introduce evaluation resources from the W3C Web Accessibility Initiative (WAI). The animated videos cover: Easy Checks — A First Review of Web Accessibility, Evaluation Tools, Conformance Evaluation including the Report Tool, and Involving Users in Web Accessibility. Other WAI videos include: Video Introduction to Web Accessibility and W3C Standards and the Web Accessibility Perspectives videos that demonstrate how accessibility is essential for some and useful for all. These videos are particularly useful to share for Global Accessibility Awareness Day (GAAD) on 21 May 2020 — along with the free online course: Introduction to Web Accessibility.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">For Review: RTC Accessibility User Requirements (RAUR) First Draft</title><link href="https://www.w3.org/WAI/news/2020-03-19/RAUR/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="For Review: RTC Accessibility User Requirements (RAUR) First Draft" /><published>2020-03-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-03-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.w3.org/WAI/news/2020-03-19/RAUR</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.w3.org/WAI/news/2020-03-19/RAUR/">&lt;p&gt;The First Public Working Draft of the Working Group Note &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.w3.org/TR/RAUR/&quot;&gt;RTC Accessibility User Requirements (RAUR)&lt;/a&gt; is now available for review. RAUR outlines user needs, requirements, and scenarios for real-time communication (RTC) to be accessible to people with disabilities. Accessible telecommunication technology is increasingly important for people who are working remotely and relying on RTC for daily needs. The purpose of this document is to inform the development of specifications and underlying architecture at W3C and beyond. Some of the requirements apply at the system or platform level, and some are authoring requirements. We would particularly like input on any user needs or requirements that are missing from this draft. For more information, see the blog post &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.w3.org/blog/2020/03/rtc-accessibility-user-requirements-call-for-review/&quot;&gt;RTC Accessibility User Requirements – Call for Review&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>W3C Web Accessibility Initiative (WAI)</name></author><summary type="html">The First Public Working Draft of the Working Group Note RTC Accessibility User Requirements (RAUR) is now available for review. RAUR outlines user needs, requirements, and scenarios for real-time communication (RTC) to be accessible to people with disabilities. Accessible telecommunication technology is increasingly important for people who are working remotely and relying on RTC for daily needs. The purpose of this document is to inform the development of specifications and underlying architecture at W3C and beyond. Some of the requirements apply at the system or platform level, and some are authoring requirements. We would particularly like input on any user needs or requirements that are missing from this draft. For more information, see the blog post RTC Accessibility User Requirements – Call for Review.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">For Review: Pronunciation of Text-To-Speech (TTS) Working Drafts</title><link href="https://www.w3.org/WAI/news/2020-03-10/pronunciation/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="For Review: Pronunciation of Text-To-Speech (TTS) Working Drafts" /><published>2020-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.w3.org/WAI/news/2020-03-10/pronunciation</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.w3.org/WAI/news/2020-03-10/pronunciation/">&lt;p&gt;New drafts of Working Group Notes are available for review: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.w3.org/TR/pronunciation-explainer/&quot;&gt;Explainer: Improving Spoken Presentation on the Web&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.w3.org/TR/pronunciation-gap-analysis-and-use-cases/&quot;&gt;Pronunciation Gap Analysis and Use Cases&lt;/a&gt;. These documents will guide work on a normative specification to enable content authors to ensure that text-to-speech (TTS) synthesis properly pronounces HTML content. We would particularly like input on additional use cases and requirements not described in these documents; and any aspects of the analysis that are missing, incorrect, or insufficiently defined. For context of this work, please see the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.w3.org/WAI/pronunciation/&quot;&gt;Pronunciation Overview&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>W3C Web Accessibility Initiative (WAI)</name></author><summary type="html">New drafts of Working Group Notes are available for review: Explainer: Improving Spoken Presentation on the Web and Pronunciation Gap Analysis and Use Cases. These documents will guide work on a normative specification to enable content authors to ensure that text-to-speech (TTS) synthesis properly pronounces HTML content. We would particularly like input on additional use cases and requirements not described in these documents; and any aspects of the analysis that are missing, incorrect, or insufficiently defined. For context of this work, please see the Pronunciation Overview.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Notice: Web Content Accessibility Guidelines (WCAG) 2.2 in Development</title><link href="https://www.w3.org/WAI/news/2020-02-27/wcag-2-2/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Notice: Web Content Accessibility Guidelines (WCAG) 2.2 in Development" /><published>2020-02-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-02-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.w3.org/WAI/news/2020-02-27/wcag-2-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.w3.org/WAI/news/2020-02-27/wcag-2-2/">&lt;p&gt;The Accessibility Guidelines Working Group (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.w3.org/WAI/GL/&quot;&gt;AG WG&lt;/a&gt;) has published a First Public Working Draft of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.w3.org/TR/WCAG22/&quot;&gt;WCAG 2.2&lt;/a&gt;. Additional success criteria in development for 2.2 address the needs of people with cognitive or learning disabilities, users of mobile devices, and users of ebooks. For information on what’s new in this draft and upcoming work, see the blog post &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.w3.org/blog/2020/02/wcag-22-in-development/&quot;&gt;Web Content Accessibility Guidelines (WCAG) 2.2 in Development&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>W3C Web Accessibility Initiative (WAI)</name></author><summary type="html">The Accessibility Guidelines Working Group (AG WG) has published a First Public Working Draft of WCAG 2.2. Additional success criteria in development for 2.2 address the needs of people with cognitive or learning disabilities, users of mobile devices, and users of ebooks. For information on what’s new in this draft and upcoming work, see the blog post Web Content Accessibility Guidelines (WCAG) 2.2 in Development.</summary></entry></feed>